<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-12-27T01:34:43+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aayushi Verma</title><subtitle>thinking slowly, learning deeply. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I Learned From My First Poster Competition</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned From My First Poster Competition"/><published>2025-03-12T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp/"><![CDATA[<p>I recently participated in my <a href="https://dailycampus.com/2025/03/11/college-of-engineering-hosts-poster-competition/">university’s College of Engineering Annual Poster Competition</a>, and won 1st place for my department (Department of Computer Science and Engineering)! This poster competition is for graduate students (Master’s and PhD) to showcase our research in a visually-compelling manner, and present it in 3 minutes or less to faculty judges outside our departments. I had a fantastic time presenting my poster, and learning from other participants. Here’s what I learned from this amazing experience!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photo of author in front of her poster at the competition. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="1-plan-in-advance">1. Plan in advance.</h2> <p>As soon as I heard about the poster competition, I started planning my course of action, namely what project I’d be presenting about, and what part of the research I thought would be most interesting for the audience to hear about. Planning in advance also gave me the opportunity to keep thinking and brainstorming about my research and how to present a condensed yet effective story.</p> <h2 id="2-know-the-rules-and-guidelines">2. Know the rules and guidelines.</h2> <p>In order to start designing my poster, it was important to know the guidelines for the competition, including the poster size and layout, presentation time, and format of competition. Knowing this information helped me prepare my poster so that I follow the rules of the competition and avoid losing any points on technicalities.</p> <h2 id="3-prepare-and-practice-the-pitch">3. Prepare and practice the pitch.</h2> <p>Designing the poster itself was fairly easy (keep reading below for my specific design tips), but ultimately the poster is just a prop for me to convey my research to the competition judges. Therefore writing the pitch script is equally important and goes hand-in-hand with poster design (again, keep reading to learn how I wrote my pitch script). Once I wrote my pitch script and was satisfied with it, I practiced, practiced, practiced! I practiced in the shower, in the car, while walking to class, while doing the dishes – basically any moment of spare time I had, I practiced my pitch! The goal was not to memorize word-for-word the script, but rather to learn the flow of specific points in my story and key terms I wanted to say.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Low-res image of author’s poster. For a high-res version, click here. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="4-get-feedback-early-and-often">4. Get feedback early and often.</h2> <p>As soon as I learned about the competition, I spoke with my advisor and asked him for feedback on the research I wanted to present – we had a fruitful discussion on the key points of the research that are important, and this feedback was really helpful for me as I designed my poster and pitch. As I worked on developing my narrative, I often got feedback from my labmates, my research collaborators, my friends and family, and even my professor from the Scientific Communication class I took last semester! This variety of feedback and perspectives helped me hone my poster and pitch.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author pitching her poster to the judges during the competition. Source: <a href="https://engineering.uconn.edu/">UConn College of Engineering</a>. </div> <h2 id="5-kiss">5. KISS.</h2> <p>Given that the poster presentation time was very short (3 minutes), I had to really think deep and convey only the most important things about my research. This meant Keeping Things Stupid Simple (KISS). I used the And, But, Therefore (ABT) storytelling framework to help me KISS. Essentially, the ABT framework is great for structuring your pitch so that it hooks the audience in, introduces the problem, and keeps them engaged to hear how you solved/are solving the problem. Read more about ABT in the ‘Resources’ section below.</p> <p>Another way I KISS-ed was by using the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs">Better Poster</a> format. This is a poster design format I like because of its visual simplicity, and focus on conveying key information in a visual manner. Essentially, the key takeaway in plain English should be placed in the middle of the poster, with 1-2 supporting key visuals. I’ve included the specific tips I used to design my poster in the ‘Resources’ section.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Whiteboard brainstorm of author’s ABT storytelling for pitch. Source: author. </div> <p>These tips helped me prepare for the competition, but here are some things I also learned from the actual day of the competition:</p> <h2 id="6-wear-comfortable-shoes">6. Wear comfortable shoes!</h2> <p>I wore a professional outfit, which called for my high-heeled boots – but to my great dismay, these boots were not as comfortable as I thought, and by the end of the event, my feet were killing me! This was a little distracting (and painful), and I wish I had worn my flat boots, because we were standing the whole time during the event (4-5 hours straight!). Oh well, I’ll remember for next time!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Group photo of department and final winners of poster competition. Author standing far left. Source: <a href="https://engineering.uconn.edu/">UConn College of Engineering</a>. </div> <h2 id="7-have-alternative-versions-of-your-pitch">7. Have alternative versions of your pitch.</h2> <p>One of my greatest learnings during this competition was the necessity to “sell your science”. The ultimate winners of the competition had one thing in common: they were able to explicitly pitch their research as a sellable product to the final round judges, who were investors from industry. The judges asked them questions like, “What is the scalable value of your product?” and received dollar amounts in response. This was an eye-opening revelation for me, as thus far I had only viewed my research as “sharing knowledge to the community”, but in reality, an alternative version of this is also a market product! In fact, many common products we use today were indeed born from academia. This is also a great skill to have in academia itself, where you apply for scholarships, fellowships and grants to support your research – by identifying a clear, real-world “return on investment” from your research, it can help in making your application stand out to funding agencies.</p> <p>Later after the competition had ended, I went up and talked to the final winner: a final-year PhD student from Material Science &amp; Engineering, who presented their research on a color-changing nano-material which is lightweight and scalable – and I learned that they are already working on running 2 startups related to their research! I was fascinated hearing them talk about their journey and research – clearly they had put in the effort to really think about the real-world value of their research! One thing they recommended for learning about “selling your science” is by attending <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Startup_accelerator">seed accelerators</a> and seed pitches. Lucky for me, UConn has a great innovation program and hosts a monthly ‘Shark Tank’ style ‘Get Seeded’ event, which I’ll definitely attend to learn more about this new (to me) frontier!</p> <h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2> <p>Ultimately, my goal for taking part in the poster competition is because I love talking about my research, and learning about my peers’ research too! What’s a more fun way to do this than a poster competition? Furthermore this is great practice for conferences and building science communication skills – I highly recommend anyone to take part in such events – no matter what level you’re at (undergrad, Master’s, PhD, or beyond!). I especially love listening to the questions I get asked about my research – it helps me understand how others perceive my work, and enables me to better understand and explain my research. Finally, it’s a great way to connect with community and build a professional network!</p> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <h4 id="how-i-designed-my-poster">How I Designed My Poster</h4> <p>I used PowerPoint to design my poster! I used &gt;90pt font size for the big takeaway statement at the top, 60pt for headers, and 36pt for main body text. I chose a color palette of shades of blue, with an accent of orange for some contrast. I matched my bar chart of results to the same color palette, and matched keywords related to each of the columns of data as well, to make it visually easy to match up. I used <a href="https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/">QRCode Monkey</a> to generate the QR code which points to the project website, and <a href="https://coolors.co/">coolors.co</a> to choose colors for my palette! One thing I forgot to include in my final version is my name and department, as I had been cycling through different versions of my poster before settling on this one, whoops!</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/">https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/</a></li> <li><a href="https://coolors.co/">https://coolors.co/</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="better-poster">Better Poster</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/6ua4k">https://osf.io/6ua4k</a></li> <li><a href="https://betterposters.blogspot.com/2019/04/critique-morrison-billboard-poster.html">https://betterposters.blogspot.com/2019/04/critique-morrison-billboard-poster.html</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="and-but-therefore">And, But, Therefore</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERB7ITvabA4&amp;t=5s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERB7ITvabA4&amp;t=5s</a></li> <li><a href="https://katrinawesencraft.com/2021/08/11/creating-a-narrative-with-and-but-therefore/">https://katrinawesencraft.com/2021/08/11/creating-a-narrative-with-and-but-therefore/</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="3mt-3-minute-thesis">3MT (3-Minute Thesis)</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.animateyour.science/post/how-to-write-a-winning-3mt-script">https://www.animateyour.science/post/how-to-write-a-winning-3mt-script</a></li> <li><a href="https://threeminutethesis.uq.edu.au/resources/3mt-competitor-guide">https://threeminutethesis.uq.edu.au/resources/3mt-competitor-guide</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="science-communication"/><category term="conferences"/><category term="data-visualization"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently participated in my university's College of Engineering Annual Poster Competition, and won 1st place for my department (Department of Computer Science and Engineering)!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Power of Positive Thinking</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Power of Positive Thinking"/><published>2025-02-28T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I was pondering whether the (metaphorical) glass is half-empty, or full.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Half-full, or half-empty? Image source: <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/close-up-shot-of-a-glass-of-water-9996342/">pexels</a>. </div> <p>A half-empty glass: it is a true statement about the glass cup, and communicates the lack of water in the glass.</p> <p>A half-full glass: it is also a true statement about the same glass cup, and communicates the presence of water in the glass.</p> <p>Now replace ‘water’ with ‘opportunity’ in the above two statements: how would you rather see your glass cup now?</p> <p>Replace ‘glass cup’ with ‘life’, and re-read the above now.</p> <p>So positive thinking affects your worldview and opens up the world for you, if you see the glass as half-full: represents opportunity, knowledge, and the joy of living! It’s all about perspective, and how we choose to see things.</p> <p>Just a little thought for the day! 🙂</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Message on a Post-It note the author wrote for herself as a reminder. Source: author. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="random"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago, I was pondering whether the (metaphorical) glass is half-empty, or full.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Old Town Alexandria</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/exploring-old-town-alexandria/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Old Town Alexandria"/><published>2024-06-30T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/exploring-old-town-alexandria</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/exploring-old-town-alexandria/"><![CDATA[<p>I recently <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lZbwKWJy8no&amp;feature=youtu.be">made a vlog</a> about my day out in Old Town, Alexandria, Virginia. Having spent almost two years living in Alexandria, I am quite familiar with Old Town and its historic charm. In this article, I go into more detail about Old Town, and the places I visited in my vlog, in order!</p> <p>TODO: embed vlog here!</p> <p>The Old Town historic district in Alexandria, Virginia is a vibrant and charming area filled with historical landmarks, cozy coffee shops, great cuisine and dining, and unique experiences. Here are the highlights from my vlog:</p> <h2 id="1-metrobus-bus-stop-at-swann-ave-0031-in-the-vlog">1. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Rt+1+%26+E+Swann+Av/@38.828707,-77.0504341,239m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0de9d453515:0x63be7e5e8fc016bf!8m2!3d38.82891!4d-77.050781!16s%2Fg%2F11b6bq2116?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Metrobus Bus Stop at Swann Ave</a> (00:31 in the vlog)</h2> <p>From where I lived in Alexandria, there are several ways to get to Old Town: driving, biking, walking, taking the Metro, or my personal favorite, taking the <a href="https://metrowayva.com/">Metroway 1 (MW1) bus</a>. The MW1 operates in a loop from the <a href="https://www.kimcorealty.com/properties/pentagon-centre/111620/view">Pentagon City Mall</a> to Braddock Station, and has a dedicated bus lane in the middle of the highway (which I point out at 00:44 in my vlog). It’s only a short 7-9 minute bus ride from the Swann Ave bus stop to Braddock Station.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Metroway bus stop at Swann Ave. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="2-braddock-metro-center-0124-in-the-vlog">2. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Braddock+Metro+Center/@38.8153514,-77.0519396,773m/data=!3m2!1e3!5s0x89b7b0e0d4a65993:0x5eeccd3dcb5c2e3c!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0fcc329e73d:0x6d48016485d7d08b!8m2!3d38.8154431!4d-77.0519025!16s%2Fg%2F11dx8gz8fb?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Braddock Metro Center</a> (01:24 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is where the MW1 drops me off, and loops around to continue its circuit. <a href="https://www.wmata.com/rider-guide/stations/braddock-road.cfm">Braddock Station</a> is a transit hub, with other buses also arriving, a Metro station, a kiss-and-ride area for cars to drop off passengers, and a Capital Bikeshare station to rent bikes. From Braddock Station, it is about a 15-minute walk to arrive at King Street, the main artery of Old Town.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Braddock Metro Station. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="3-united-states-post-office-0200-in-the-vlog">3. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/United+States+Postal+Service/@38.8132836,-77.0505615,773m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0fb81554ead:0xb17188b8623ce9b3!8m2!3d38.8123923!4d-77.050359!16s%2Fg%2F11h1ll_g_?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">United States Post Office</a> (02:00 in the vlog)</h2> <p>I needed to get <a href="https://www.usps.com/international/first-class-mail-international.htm">Global Forever Stamps</a> to send my friend in New Zealand a postcard, so I stopped by the <a href="https://www.usps.com/">USPS</a>. It’s a very convenient 4-minute walk from Braddock Station, and I love the historic brick exterior.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> United States Postal Service (USPS). Source: author. </div> <h2 id="4-mishas-coffee-0310-in-the-vlog">4. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Misha's/@38.8058772,-77.0482507,772m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b1412f2edc0b:0xfbfe4ba257c66592!8m2!3d38.80565!4d-77.0497329!16s%2Fg%2F1tsyqn_z?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Misha’s Coffee</a> (03:10 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is one of my <a href="https://mishascoffee.com/">all-time favorite coffeeshops</a> in Alexandria (and Alexandria has a really great coffee scene!). They have a large variety of coffee beans, which they roast and grind in-house. They also offer an amazing selection of pastries. I got an Everything Bagel with cream cheese and an Iced Chai Latte – both very good and delicious! One of the many reasons I love Misha’s is their working space at the back. The lighting is focused, and there’s good jazz music playing in the background. Last year, while finishing up my Master’s degree, I often went to Misha’s on weekends for the vibes – it was very conducive to getting all my assignments done!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Misha's Coffee iconic sign outside the cafe. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="5-lilys-chocolate-and-coffee-0419-in-the-vlog">5. <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/9xs7nK7uqU1gmzMJ8">Lily’s Chocolate and Coffee</a> (04:19 in the vlog)</h2> <p><a href="https://lilyschocolatecoffee.com/alexandria-va/">This is another great coffeeshop</a>, just 2 blocks down the street from Misha’s! They opened last year in 2023, and have a great selection of pastries and coffee. Their interior décor is very photogenic – perfect for Instagram!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Looking inside Lily's Chocolate and Coffee cafe. It's very pink and snap-worthy! Source: author. </div> <h2 id="6-old-town--town-square-0440-and-0925-in-the-vlog">6. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Old+Town+Farmers'+Market/@38.8049719,-77.0439998,205m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f7db3a25f3:0x3bf07285271b91e6!8m2!3d38.8048475!4d-77.0430439!16s%2Fg%2F1td77gjb?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Old Town – Town Square</a> (04:40 and 09:25 in the vlog)</h2> <p><a href="https://visitalexandria.com/listings/alexandria-city-hall-market-square/">This is a central part of Old Town</a>! Every Saturday from 7am-noon, there’s a <a href="https://www.alexandriava.gov/OldTownFarmersMarket">Farmer’s Market</a> hosted in the Town Square. Additionally, at Christmas, there’s an <a href="https://apps.alexandriava.gov/Calendar/Detail.aspx?si=53385">annual Christmas Tree tradition</a> where they light the tree! The building in the backdrop is the Alexandria City Hall, designated a National Historic Landmark.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Fresh produce at Farmer's Market. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="7-kate-waller-barrett-branch-library-0517-in-the-vlog">7. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kate+Waller+Barrett+Branch+Library/@38.806366,-77.046886,531m/data=!3m2!1e3!5s0x89b7b0f9b71d941b:0xe1b804a71fe703ae!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f9adc8cf63:0x929bdf9d12275e4!8m2!3d38.8077995!4d-77.0471567!16s%2Fm%2F040_8js?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Kate Waller Barrett Branch Library</a> (05:17 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is my <a href="https://alexlibraryva.org/barrett">favorite library in Alexandria</a>. It’s very community-oriented, and there are constantly lots of events and workshops hosted by the library! They also regularly have little booksales for very cheap – for a grand total of $4, I got two books in great condition (<a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/561709/the-back-channel-by-william-j-burns/">The Back Channel</a>, and <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/noresults/on-the-way-to-christmas-sheila-roberts/1141293176">On The Way to Christmas</a>)! There are a lot of working spaces, and the views from the windows are so beautiful, especially in the fall!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Entrance to Kate Waller Barrett branch library. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="8-turkish-coffee-lady-0641-in-the-vlog">8. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Turkish+Coffee+Lady/@38.8059337,-77.0508155,117m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b64ae8bb84aa33:0xe32d07c6cec170df!8m2!3d38.8056758!4d-77.0503861!16s%2Fg%2F11h9y6jqv9?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Turkish Coffee Lady</a> (06:41 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is a very unique and cultural coffeeshop experience in Old Town! It’s a <a href="https://turkishcoffeelady.com/">local woman-owned coffeeshop</a>, bringing the Turkish experience to you. It’s a small but cozy café, tastefully decorated with Turkish and Middle Eastern influences. I got their classic Turkish coffee and a spinach-feta pastry. The coffee comes in a little tray with three items: a cup of water, a mug of Turkish coffee, and some Turkish Delight jellies. First, you take a sip of water to cleanse your palate. The next step is to drink some of the Turkish coffee – but keep it in your mouth, and eat some of the Turkish Delight! Chewing the jelly with the bitter coffee adds a delicious flavor profile to the coffee experience!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Pastry and coffee that I ordered at Turkish Coffee Lady cafe. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="9-stabler-leadbeater-apothecary-museum-0948-and-1054-in-the-vlog">9. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Stabler-Leadbeater+Apothecary+Museum/@38.8043436,-77.0425758,120m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f7d8002b51:0x3c9d3933322bfb29!8m2!3d38.8042309!4d-77.0427898!16s%2Fm%2F03wbwmz?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Stabler-Leadbeater Apothecary Museum</a> (09:48 and 10:54 in the vlog)</h2> <p><a href="https://www.alexandriava.gov/Apothecary">This museum</a> is a very unique experience of historic Old Town! It used to be an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apothecary">apothecary</a> founded in 1790s Alexandria by William Stabler, and was a family business. They sold various herbal remedies, medicines, and chemical tinctures, and manufactured their own medicines too. They eventually closed down in the 1930s, after which the citizens of Alexandria bought and preserved the Apothecary as a museum for us to now tour and learn more about pre-modern medicine!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Various chemical and herbal materials stored as-is at the Apothecary museum. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="10-alexandria-visitor-center-1011-in-the-vlog">10. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Alexandria+Visitor+Center+(Ramsay+House)/@38.8045,-77.0423903,120m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f7d3bac71b:0x1979292718ad1516!8m2!3d38.8046223!4d-77.0423542!16s%2Fg%2F1tnjkg6d?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Alexandria Visitor Center</a> (10:11 in the vlog)</h2> <p>The <a href="https://visitalexandria.com/plan/visitor-center/">Visitor Center</a> is a great resource for figuring out all the cool things to do in Old Town and Alexandria! There are lots of free brochures and guides, and there’s even a little gift shop to buy Alexandria and Virginia merch. I didn’t mention this in the vlog, but they also organize <a href="https://www.alexcolonialtours.com/">walking Colonial Ghost Tours</a> at night! It’s a great experience to walk around with a Colonial-attired tour guide, showing you all the historic sights around Old Town with a side of ghost stories!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Old Town (aka Alexandria Historic District) is a designated national historical landmark. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="11-the-principle-gallery-1040-in-the-vlog">11. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/laura+e.+pritchett/@38.8043749,-77.0418118,47m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f62b78b14d:0xf895f2687919641c!8m2!3d38.8044113!4d-77.0418684!16s%2Fg%2F11dxnnl6z3?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">The Principle Gallery</a> (10:40 in the vlog)</h2> <p>I was walking around the streets, killing time until my timed tour for the Stabler-Leadbeater Apothecary museum, when I stumbled across this <a href="https://www.principlegallery.com/alexandria/">art gallery</a>. It was very interesting looking at the pretty art!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some beautiful (but expensive) art in the gallery. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="12-lou-lou-boutiques-1219-in-the-vlog">12. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Lou+Lou+Boutiques/@38.8043193,-77.0414416,49m/data=!3m2!1e3!5s0x89b7b0f627ddc28f:0xe079b59986498e78!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f6287177f9:0xa207c19ad13b3089!8m2!3d38.8042633!4d-77.0413967!16s%2Fg%2F1tdlclzx?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Lou Lou Boutiques</a> (12:19 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is a <a href="https://www.loulouboutiques.com/pages/alx">little store</a> my friend showed me a while ago, where they sell clothes, body care, jewelry, and more. I popped in to see if I could get the same friend a birthday present from here, and I ended up getting her a fancy soap and lip balm – she loved it!</p> <h2 id="13-mai-thai-restaurant-1238-in-the-vlog">13. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Mai+Thai+Restaurant/@38.8042172,-77.0403003,50m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f61d036b67:0x36e4e7a75cfd1bc3!8m2!3d38.8040657!4d-77.0400369!16s%2Fg%2F11ddxvx_xg?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Mai Thai Restaurant</a> (12:38 in the vlog)</h2> <p>This is one of my <a href="https://maithai.com/oldtown/">favorite restaurants</a> in Old Town by the waterfront, and I love sitting in their outdoor seating area whenever possible, especially beautiful summer days like this day. My sister and mum joined me for dinner, and we got Gyoza (green fried wontons) for appetizers, Drunken Noodles and Mixed Vegetable Jae (tofu dish) for our main dishes, and a non-alcoholic Pina Colada for our drink. I love the food here, it’s very spicy and there’s a lot of good vegetarian options!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Our dinner! Left - Drunken Noodles, right - Mixed Vegetable Jae, top - Gyoza. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="14-pops-ice-cream-1259-in-the-vlog">14. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Pop's+Old+Fashion+Ice+Cream+Co/@38.8044315,-77.0407361,50m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f6228796e3:0x5e64e178257056c!8m2!3d38.8043859!4d-77.0407048!16s%2Fg%2F1thl_b4b?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Pop’s Ice Cream</a> (12:59 in the vlog)</h2> <p>Next, for dessert, we walked right across the street to <a href="https://www.popsoldfashionedicecream.com/">Pop’s Old-Fashioned Ice Cream parlor</a>. They have a lot of great ice cream and gelato options, and it was very hard to make up our minds on what flavors we wanted! I ended up getting a scoop of Butter Pecan, and my sister got a scoop of pistachio and a scoop of cookies and cream. All three flavors were very good!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My ice cream cone - waffle cone with a scoop of Butter Pecan. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="15-waterfront-art-installation-1400-in-the-vlog">15. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Waterfront+Public+Art+Installation/@38.8040265,-77.0397009,101m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b10524eebe3b:0x5497559afb5edff9!8m2!3d38.8039462!4d-77.0395825!16s%2Fg%2F11swkx0hnf?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Waterfront Art Installation</a> (14:00 in the vlog)</h2> <p>Since we were all very full from dinner and ice cream, we decided to walk around the Waterfront area. Right across from Mai Thai and Pop’s Ice Cream is an art installation, which changes every so often. The current exhibition is called ‘<a href="https://visitalexandria.com/public-art/">Interstellar Influencer</a>‘, on display until Nov. 2024. It resembles a geometric metallic asteroid, with mist coming off it!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Art installation by the waterfront, titled 'Interstellar Visitor'. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="16-waterfront-boat-dock-1405-in-the-vlog">16. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Alexandria/@38.8051905,-77.0393209,100m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7b0f5e7638537:0x337fa8ee66a64748!8m2!3d38.8051418!4d-77.0392249!16s%2Fg%2F11g21w6blm?entry=tts&amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDYyNi4wKgBIAVAD">Waterfront Boat Dock</a> (14:05 in the vlog)</h2> <p>Finally, continuing along the Waterfront, I got a timelapse of the <a href="https://visitalexandria.com/things-to-do/waterfront-activities/boat-tours/">boat dock</a>, and of people walking along the boardwalk. It was very nice and relaxing!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View of boats and Potomac River from the waterfront. Source: author. </div> <p>Spending a day in Old Town Alexandria was an absolute delight. From the charming coffee shops to the historic landmarks and the beautiful waterfront, there’s always something new and exciting to discover. Whether you’re a local or a visitor, Old Town offers a unique blend of history, culture, and modern-day attractions that make it a must-visit destination.</p> <p>I hope you enjoyed reading about my adventures and found some inspiration for your own visit. Be sure to check out <a href="youtube.com/watch?v=lZbwKWJy8no&amp;feature=youtu.be">my vlog</a> for a more immersive experience, where I take you through each of these fantastic spots in real time! Happy exploring!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently made a vlog about my day out in Old Town, Alexandria, Virginia.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Watched The April 2024 Solar Eclipse!</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/apr2024-solar-eclipse/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Watched The April 2024 Solar Eclipse!"/><published>2024-04-12T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-12T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/apr2024-solar-eclipse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/apr2024-solar-eclipse/"><![CDATA[<p>On Monday 8th April, 2024, I witnessed an incredible thing: a total solar eclipse. There are no words for this experience, and yet in this article, I’ll find them and describe just how amazing it was! I also recorded a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a> narrating my live experiences watching the solar eclipse!</p> <p>TODO: embed vlog here!</p> <p>The last time there was a total solar eclipse visible from North America, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solar_eclipse_of_August_21,_2017">it was 2017</a>. I was in New Zealand at the time, so I missed out. I consoled myself with the fact that the next solar eclipse was in 2024 – 7 years later – and that I’d make sure not to miss it that time.</p> <p>Fast-forward to 2024, the time has come for the solar eclipse, and the path of 100% <a href="https://eclipse.aas.org/eclipse-america/eclipse-glossary">totality</a> is at minimum a 6-hour drive from where I live in Virginia, and at most 11 hours (if I wanted to go all the way up to Maine or Vermont). There was no way I was going to miss totality this time, so I convinced my family to make the arduous journey to see 100% totality. <a href="https://patch.com/virginia/oldtownalexandria/2024-solar-eclipse-when-look-virginia">Virginia was going to see 88% totality</a>, which isn’t the same, and for the price of a relatively short road trip, why not see 100% totality?</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Path of totality, and our journey to see the eclipse. Source: timeanddate.com, edited by author. </div> <h2 id="planning-the-trip">Planning the trip</h2> <p>After consulting <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/map/2024-april-8">this useful map of the solar eclipse path</a>, we decided to go to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cleveland">Cleveland, Ohio</a> for three reasons: 1. to see the solar eclipse at 100% totality, 2. to visit our family friends who live there, and 3. to check off Ohio as another state I’ve visited on my <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/aayushi.verma/viz/my_world_exploration_map/PlacesIveBeen?publish=yes">world travel map</a>.</p> <p>In preparation for this trip, I ordered <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C6N2WP18?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_product_details&amp;th=1">this 10-pack of eclipse viewing glasses</a> from Amazon to share with everyone we’d be viewing with. We didn’t have to book any flights or hotels, since we were driving and staying with our family friends, but we did have to plan for traffic carefully. This is because <a href="https://www.greatamericaneclipse.com/visitation">anywhere from 1-3 million people would be traveling to see the eclipse, in addition to the 31 million people who already live in the path of totality</a>. We decided to drive from VA to OH on Saturday 6th, and return back on Tuesday 9th.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some beautiful scenery in rural Pennsylvania during our drive to Ohio! Source: author. </div> <h2 id="watching-the-solar-eclipse">Watching the solar eclipse</h2> <p>On the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQ1L75DAmvI">morning of Monday 8th, it was totally clouded over</a>! I was nervous that maybe we wouldn’t be able to see totality after all, but miraculously the clouds cleared up around 11am and stayed that way! Our family friends took us to a nearby park to watch the eclipse, and interestingly there wasn’t a lot of traffic on the roads, nor a lot of people at the park! Thank goodness for quiet suburbs.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author and her family friends’ eclipse-viewing party! Source: author. </div> <p>We set up shop in a corner of the park, and I set up my tripod and phone, ready to take photos of the eclipse when it started. However, seeing my phone just sit there on the tripod doing nothing made me think, why not narrate my experiences during the eclipse? And so I started vlogging my solar eclipse experience! I edited it into a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author’s eclipse-viewing rig! Source: author’s mum. </div> <p>In Cleveland, <a href="https://www.clevelandmetroparks.com/parks/education/education-programs/2024-solar-eclipse">these were the key eclipse-viewing times</a>:</p> <ul> <li>Eclipse started at 1.59pm.</li> <li>Totality started at 3.13pm.</li> <li>Maximum was at 3.15pm.</li> <li>Totality ended at 3.17pm.</li> <li>Eclipse ended at 4.29pm.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author’s attempt at photographing the solar eclipse by placing spare eclipse glasses over her phone’s camera lens. Not too bad, right? Source: author. </div> <p>It was incredible seeing the moon slowly eclipse the sun from the bottom-right corner, moving up to the top-left corner.</p> <p>As it was getting closer to totality, it was <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/eclipses/">getting colder</a> and darker, because the moon was blocking the path of light from the sun. This is obviously what usually happens every day when the sun sets, but seeing it happen in the middle of the day was a little jarring! In fact, it got so cold that I wanted to put on a sweater, even though it was previously about 70 degrees Fahrenheit (~21 degrees Celsius).</p> <p>As the Moon started eclipsing the Sun closer to 100% during totality, I saw the famous <a href="https://www.greatamericaneclipse.com/double-diamond-ring">diamond ring effect</a>, but did not see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baily%27s_beads">Baily’s Beads</a> due to low-quality eclipse glasses. I also saw a ‘red dot’ at the bottom of the sun, which I later learned was actually a <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/red-dots-around-total-solar-eclipse-explained/">solar prominence</a>, a magnetized loop of plasma on the Sun’s surface! I also saw <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/14563">Jupiter and Venus emerge</a> around the Sun during totality, now that they weren’t being dimmed by the brightness of the Sun!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The sun covered by the moon during totality! Source: author. </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Venus (bottom-right corner) was visible during totality, when the moon blocked out enough of the sun’s light. Source: author. </div> <p>During totality, the surrounding sky looked like a sunset sky, with the Sun’s remaining light being reflected in the clouds opposite, like how I point out in my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a> (at 15:37). The geese in the park got very confused and started squawking and flying like crazy, which goes to show <a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20240405-solar-eclipse-2024-effect-on-animals">how animals are also affected by the eclipse</a>.</p> <p>Just before totality, I noted in my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a> that my surroundings started appearing grey-ish to me (at 12:50 in the vlog). This was because of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purkinje_effect#:~:text=The%20Purkinje%20effect%20or%20Purkinje,as%20part%20of%20dark%20adaptation.">Purkinje effect</a>, where the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rod_cell">rod</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cone_cell">cone</a> cells in our eyes are adapting to the change in light intensity! <a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-colors-different-total-eclipse">This article by sciencenews.org</a> describes this effect during eclipses.</p> <p>Eventually totality ended, and the darkness started receding. I continued observing the Moon’s shadow leave the Sun, but now in the opposite direction that it had approached. As I reflected on the experience, I realized that nothing could compare to the feeling of being in totality. It was a very unique experience, and I truly understand why people become eclipse-hunters – I know I would do anything to experience totality again!</p> <h2 id="reflections">Reflections</h2> <blockquote> <p>Nothing holds a candle to totality.</p> </blockquote> <p>At 20:57 in my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a>, I said the above quote when attempting to describe my experience during totality. It was truly a life-changing experience, which really made me contemplate how lucky we are to experience such a fantastical cosmic phenomenon. I did <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0fgbMTC30F8">some research on the orbital mechanics that needed to occur for this solar eclipse to happen</a>, and it truly astounds me.</p> <p>Now that the solar eclipse is over, we all have to go on with our mundane lives. But we can <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/list.html">hope to see another eclipse like this one soon</a>. There are a <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/eclipses/types/">few annular and partial eclipses</a> from now to 2026. The <a href="https://www.space.com/stargazing/eclipses/top-solar-eclipses-next-decade">next total solar eclipses</a> will be across Europe in Aug. 2026, northern Africa in 2027, and Australia and New Zealand in 2028. There’s a lot of opportunities if you missed out this time or if it was cloudy!</p> <p>At the start of my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbGUfmDSVyg&amp;feature=youtu.be">vlog</a>, I raise the question if it was worth driving 6 hours just for a chance to see the eclipse. I answer that question now: yes, it absolutely was. It truly was the experience of a lifetime. I must thank my family for going along with my craziness and driving us up to Ohio, and I am especially most grateful to our family friends, who very kindly hosted us, and took us to see sunset over Lake Erie, and took us to a prime viewing location for the eclipse. &lt;3</p> <p>Here’s to the next solar eclipse!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Sunset over Lake Erie. Source: author. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel,"/><category term="astronomy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Monday 8th April, 2024, I witnessed an incredible thing - a total solar eclipse.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tableau Conference 2023 - My Experience</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/tableau-conference-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tableau Conference 2023 - My Experience"/><published>2024-02-19T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-19T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/tableau-conference-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/tableau-conference-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>As a data scientist, I use <a href="https://www.tableau.com/">Tableau</a> a lot to make interactive dashboards for my business stakeholders to consume key insights. I realized that while I use Tableau a lot, there’s still a lot for me to learn — and what’s a better way to learn than attending a conference about it? In this article, I describe my experience attending the 2023 <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/tableau-conference/">Tableau Conference</a> in Las Vegas!</p> <p><em>Note: this article was originally drafted in May 2023, but finally published now in Feb. 2024!</em></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author posing in between larger-than-life DATA letters at conference, holding up a sign that says ‘I (heart) DATA’. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="what-is-tableauconference">What is Tableau/Conference?</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Example of a Tableau dashboard from one of its ‘stock’ demo examples. Source: Tableau. </div> <p>Tableau is a business intelligence software for making interactive dashboards. It’s a great way to provide stakeholders with an interactive (and often pretty-looking) interface to data, whether live or static. Tableau, as an organization, has a great community, and hosts this conference every year, even after <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/products/tableau/">SalesForce acquired the company</a>. The community very proudly refers to themselves as ‘<a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/products/tableau/">DataFam</a>’, and it was easy to see why, because the speakers and attendees at the conference were so vibrant and enthusiastic in their passion for data visualization.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Decor near conference’s main entrance. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="tableau-conference-2023">Tableau Conference 2023</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Registration area for conference. Source: author. </div> <p>The conference was hosted in Las Vegas from May 9–11 this year. I was surprised to learn that there would be more than 8000 people attending this year. There were so many events to choose from, including talks, workshops, community meet-ups, vendor booths, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8c6ZgrPR9Gk">Tableau Doctor</a>, <a href="https://www.tableau.com/blog/2023-iron-viz-2023-championship">IronViz Showdown</a>, Data Village, and more.</p> <p>As a result, I really had to focus on what exactly I wanted to accomplish by attending the conference. For me, this was learning about the more advanced features of Tableau, and how to approach problems and solutions in Tableau. This helped me choose the most relevant sessions, and I will summarize my key learnings from each of these below.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author’s scheduled sessions for conference. Author added multiple sessions in parallel to allow for flexibility, but wishes she had a time-turner to attend all of them simultaneously. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="my-experience">My Experience</h2> <p>At the time of attending the conference, I was working on building a Tableau dashboard at work, which needed to perform complex actions, called ‘<a href="https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/actions_sets.htm">set</a>’ and ‘<a href="https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/actions_parameters.htm">parameter</a>’ actions. These are functions for interacting with and passing data parameters to create interactivity in the dashboard. As a result, many of the sessions and workshops I attended were focused on learning about and using these set/parameter actions.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author attending a hands-on session (titled: A Producer’s Guide to Set Actions). Source: author. </div> <p>I also attended sessions about the art of data visualization and best practices, about using calculated fields, and even a Women in Data Strategy panel.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Women in Data Strategy panel. Source: author. </div> <p>The session that amazed me the most was the IronViz Competition, where three competitors had 20 minutes on-stage to create a dashboard from scratch! The energy in the stadium was incredible, and as we cheered on the three contestants, seeing their dashboard progress appear on the big screen, it was very nail-biting and lots of twists and turns right until the end!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Celebration of IronViz 2023 winner, Paul Ross. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="key-impressions-and-takeaways">Key Impressions and Takeaways</h2> <p>In the three short days I attended this conference, I learned a lot and interacted with a lot of amazing people. Some of my positive impressions:</p> <ul> <li>Huge DataFam community!</li> <li>Lots of inventive ways to use Tableau.</li> <li>Future integrations with LLMs, AI, etc.</li> <li>Very commercial — lots of vendor stalls.</li> <li>Need to think differently when using Tableau.</li> <li>There is so much that you can get out of Tableau Conference — it really depends on your reason for attending.</li> </ul> <p>Organizing large conferences is not an easy task, and I truly respect the organizers and volunteers who put in a lot of effort in making the conference a success. However, some of the things I wish they had done better:</p> <ul> <li>There were too many people, and not enough space in the session rooms.</li> <li>There were too many great sessions scheduled at the same time, so I had to miss out on a lot of these.</li> <li>Barely any sessions were recorded for later viewing.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photo from conference photobooth, with author holding up a sign that says ‘I (heart) DATA’. Source: author. </div> <p>In terms of my goal for attending the conference, which was to learn about using set and parameter actions, I definitely achieved it. I learned about different tools and methods to exploit set, parameter and dashboard actions to increase the interactivity and effectiveness of the dashboard. One of the ideas that was constantly reinforced was the idea of keeping the stakeholder in mind, and designing the dashboard to convey insights from the date as effectively as possible. Also, never be afraid to get creative!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Swag from Tableau Conference 2023. Includes t-shirts, notebook, fanny pack, stickers, badges, a really cute llama, and more. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="las-vegas--nevada">Las Vegas + Nevada</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View from escalators when exiting Harry Reid International Airport after arrival in Las Vagas. Source: author. </div> <p>This was my first time visiting Las Vegas, so I was very excited! I stayed at the <a href="https://mgmgrand.mgmresorts.com/en.html">MGM Grand hotel</a>, and had the opportunity to explore the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Las_Vegas_Strip">Las Vegas Strip</a> on my days off. There were a lot of tourist-y attractions like <a href="https://www.mms.com/en-us/explore/mms-stores/las-vegas">M&amp;Ms Chocolate Factory</a>, <a href="https://hersheyschocolateworldlasvegas.com/">Hershey’s Chocolate Factory</a>, etc., but there were also a lot of other recognizable landmarks to see, like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fountains_of_Bellagio">Bellagio Fountain</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_the_Lion_(MGM)">Leo the Lion</a>, the mini <a href="https://newyorknewyork.mgmresorts.com/en.html">New York along the strip</a>, and more.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_the_Lion_(MGM)">Leo the Lion</a> outside of MGM Grand Hotel. Source: author. </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fountains_of_Bellagio">Bellagio Fountain</a> light and water show. Source: author. </div> <p>I also had the chance to visit the Hoover Dam, where I walked across the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_O%27Callaghan%E2%80%93Pat_Tillman_Memorial_Bridge">Mike O’Callaghan Pat Tillman Memorial Bridge</a> and got a spectacular birds-eye view of the Hoover Dam below me. I also visited the actual Hoover Dam, and learned about its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hoover_Dam">history, construction and legacy</a>, and got to see the power plant below the Dam.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Hoover Dam photos! Source: author. </div> <p>Overall, I really enjoyed my time in Vegas (and by extension, Nevada). The landscape was beautiful, and it was great experiencing that part of the country, since it’s very different from the East Coast. Next time I’m in the area, I will visit the Grand Canyon so I can also check off Arizona on my <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/aayushi.verma/viz/my_world_exploration_map/PlacesIveBeen?publish=yes">travel list</a>!</p> <h2 id="concluding-thoughts">Concluding Thoughts</h2> <p>Attending the Tableau Conference was very worthwhile, as I got to learn more about Tableau and how to do cool things with it. I have a better understanding now about advanced dashboarding actions, and bringing the best insights through well-designed dashboards. Some further reading:</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://godatadrive.com/blog/tableau-conference-2024">Tableau Conference 2024 - Everything You Need to Know Before You Go</a></li> <li><a href="https://sarahlovesdata.co.uk/2023/03/31/tableau-conference-guide-2023-data23/">Tableau Conference Guide 2023 #data23</a></li> <li><a href="https://sarahlovesdata.co.uk/2022/04/27/tableau-conference-attendee-guide-2022-data22/">Tableau Conference Attendee Guide 2022 #data22</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="conferences,"/><category term="data-science"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a data scientist, I use Tableau a lot to make interactive dashboards for my business stakeholders to consume key insights.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SpaceCom Expo 2024 - My Experience</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/spacecom-conference-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SpaceCom Expo 2024 - My Experience"/><published>2024-02-04T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-04T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/spacecom-conference-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/spacecom-conference-2024/"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, I attended the SpaceCom Expo and Conference in Orlando, Florida. In this article, I talk about the conference, my experiences, and some other fun things I did in Florida!</p> <p>SpaceCom attendees get special mission patches and a decorative medallion! There’s a story behind the design of these patches, interestingly! Source: author. What is SpaceCom?</p> <p>Rotating ‘Commercial Space Week 2024’ globe at the conference. Source: author. SpaceCom is an event to bring together space professionals working across industry, government, academia, and more during Commercial Space Week. It actually comprises of multiple events being held at the same location (Orange Country Convention Center):</p> <p>SpaceCom | Space Congress — this is the official event name. There’s two parts in the name, which mean different things: ‘SpaceCom’ is a huge exhibition/expo, with hundreds of exhibitors demonstrating their space technologies, products, and services. ‘Space Congress’ is a conference featuring keynotes, panels, networking, and more from industry experts, thought leaders, and innovators across four tracks: Commercial Space Infrastructure, Off-Planet Commercialization, Space Exploration, and Space Innovations. Space Mobility Conference — the U.S. Space Force and Space Systems Command co-host this single-day conference. It features keynotes and panels from government, defense/military, and national security experts on dynamic space operations, commercial support for military space operations, rapid delivery to/from space, spaceport resiliency, and more. Annual GSA Spaceport Summit— this is also a single-day conference hosted by the Global Spaceport Alliance (GSA) as a forum to focus on the future commercial global network of spaceports. I didn’t attend this one, though. My motivation for attending this conference was to learn as much as possible about the space industry from both public and private-sector perspectives. Given my background in astronomy (BSc Astronomy) and data science (MS Data Science), I want to learn about technological challenges that exist in the space domain and where I can fit in, and what’s a better way than immersing myself in this conference for 3 days straight where I can hear from experts?</p> <p>My Experience I attended the Space Mobility conference and the SpaceCom | Space Congress conference over three days. In this section, I recap my learnings from the sessions I attended.</p> <p>Day One: Tue 30 Jan — Space Mobility Conference</p> <p>Lt. Col. Michael Killings from the U.S. Space Force opening the Space Mobility conference. Source: author. This was an interesting day, and I learned about the government/military perspective, since most of the keynote and panel speakers were from the U.S. Space Force and other associated military branches and government organizations. Here are my key learnings and takeaways from the talks and panel discussions:</p> <p>The National Space Council passes space-related legislation drafts to the White House, thus shaping the United States’ space policies. China is making very rapid advances in the civilian and military space domain, and this pace must be matched by the U.S. to deter aggression. The Space Force and related agencies are building a solid path for assured access to our space portfolio, which is key for national security, defense, and public safety. The space industry as a whole is moving towards sustainability in space (think reusable rocket boosters and modules). The U.S. military, especially Space Force, has collaboration with industry and academia at the forefront of their minds, to build a meaningful partnership that benefits all parties (commercial and military). We need to get out of the mindset of “because that’s the way it’s always been done”, and look for unconventional ways to innovate, so we can move fast to meet needs. In order to promote better collaboration, the military needs to think about how to provide easier access to information — whether this is re-evaluating the way security clearances are granted to people from industry, or figuring out how to use government funding in a flexible manner. The lines between what is considered military technology and what is considered civilian/commercial technology are very blurred, especially in the space domain. Spaceports should be considered ‘critical infrastructure’. Some areas the Space Force and related agencies are focused on include: space access, mobility and logistics (SAML), in-orbit refueling, space domain awareness, in-space servicing, assembly and manufacturing (ISAM), and more. Below are some quotes from the talks and panels which I found memorable.</p> <p>“Now is the time to act.” — Dr. Diane Howard (National Space Council)</p> <p>“The industry’s going a mile a minute, and I love the innovation.” — Col. Richard Kniseley (U.S. Space Force)</p> <p>“Our nation needs assured access to space.” — Ret. Maj. Gen. Ted Mercer Jr. (Virginia Spaceport Authority)</p> <p>Day Two: Wed 31 Jan — Space Congress Day #1</p> <p>The opening screen for Space Congress. Source: author. I continued to learn more about the space industry today, especially from the commercial/industry perspective. Some brief summaries of the talks and panel discussions I attended today:</p> <p>NASA is very focused on advancing Earth, lunar, Martian, and space exploration in 2024 and beyond, through multiple initiatives (Artemis-II, Quesst X-59, Moon to Mars architecture, NASA 2040, and more). Space technologies permeate every aspect of our lives (think imaging technology, fire-retardant clothing, GPS, etc.), and every industry should have a ‘space plan’ for how they use/work with these technologies. The United Launch Alliance (ULA) is the largest ‘rocket factory’ in the world today. It was not always this way — 10 years ago, ULA exclusively supported U.S. national security missions, but they changed their strategy and went commercial, embraced competition, and repositioned their product line to meet market needs globally. The state of Florida, under the administration of Ron DeSantis, is the best place right now for space, with its $1.5 trillion economy, and a clear vision by the DeSantis administration to expand Florida’s aerospace industry by investing in education, healthcare, workforce development, veterans, the semiconductor industry, and more. Artificial intelligence has very important applications in space (astronaut safety, data &amp; predictive analytics, remote sensing, and more), but it is not trustworthy yet, and needs human-in-the-loop capabilities and guardrails. Private and commercial investment has not only grown rapidly, but has also diversified across every industry. Additionally, it’s a non-localized domain, which means that any event in space affects all players, regardless of geopolitics. That being said, geopolitics is a real consideration for all decisions. Transferable skills are very valuable in the space sector, given how multidisciplinary it is. One doesn’t necessarily need a degree in engineering to be a part of the space industry — in fact we’re seeing a lot of non-traditional education and career paths in this sector. The government (especially Space Force) needs to put out clear demand signals, and work with industry and commercial partners, both domestically and globally, to reach our goals. They have an unofficial motto, “Buy what you can, build what you must”, which is really key for mission success at scale. The Space Force, Air Force, and other branches of military are thinking about how to get younger generations (Gen Z, Gen Alpha) interested in serving our country. One way they are connecting with these younger people is by setting up gaming hubs, for example, to allow them to socialize with each other in a way they’re already used to. The games these generations have grown up with (for example Call of Duty) require strategy, thinking, collaboration, etc. which translate very well to military service. They’re also using virtual and augmented reality technologies to train the younger generations! Some more memorable quotes from today’s speakers:</p> <p>“No sector in Florida is taking off more than the aerospace industry, both literally and figuratively.” — Jeanette Núñez (Lieutenant Governor of Florida)</p> <p>“The future is here, it’s just not evenly distributed.” — Owen Brown (Scientific Systems)</p> <p>“Every opportunity is also a risk.” — Neil Mickelson (Booz Allen Hamilton)</p> <p>“Turn that data into information that can help with better decision-making.” — Dr. Nelli Babayan (Microsoft Federal)</p> <p>Day Three: Thu 1 Feb — Space Congress Day #2</p> <p>Former NASA astronaut, José Hernández, giving a keynote talk about his life journey. Source: author. This was the final day full of interesting panels and keynotes. Here’s a brief summary of the talks and panels I attended today:</p> <p>All of NASA’s centers have their own areas of research and applications that they specialize in, and they collaborate with each other to serve the mission, for example Moon to Mars. José Hernández, a former NASA astronaut, gave an amazing keynote about his inspirational journey from migrant child to NASA astronaut, and how he persevered to achieve his goal of becoming an astronaut. He’s retired now, but owns and operates his own farm/vineyard, has a biopic movie based on his life story, consults in the aerospace industry, and runs his own charitable foundation! In-Space Assembly and Manufacturing (ISAM) is critical for humanity to really become space-faring. ISAM technologies will enable us to build and deploy things in space, instead of using Earth’s resources — but we need a ‘testbed’ to test various applications, for example semiconductor material growth, autonomous robotic movement, and more. Additionally, we need to make sure these technologies are reusable, sustainable, and modular to really provide best value and growth opportunities. One of the biggest problems in space is the huge volumes of data (for example, NOAA produces over 20 terabytes of data every day) being captured by satellites and downlinked to Earth. It raises questions to how to best collect and process this data, and if that much data is even necessary. Again, some more thought-provoking quotes from today’s speakers:</p> <p>“As a community, we aren’t yet asking ‘how to do it?’, from the autonomous perspective.” — Dr. Danette Allen (NASA Langley Research Center)</p> <p>“We are a silicon-based society.” — Dr. Jessica Frick (Stanford University)</p> <p>“There’s no such thing as a good model, but some are useful.” — Dr. Rusty Powell (Axient)</p> <p>All Days: SpaceCom Expo</p> <p>There were over 200 exhibitors at the expo from every part of the industry. There were manufacturing and rocket component companies, software and data analytics companies, literal rocket launch companies, space education companies, NASA, Space Force Association, and many more. I enjoyed chatting with the exhibitors and learning about how they help support the space industry. It was an eye-opening experience for me to learn about how diverse the space industry is! Plus the ton of swag I got was a sweet bonus!</p> <p>Some of the really cool swag I got from exhibitors includes (but not limited to) a NASA calendar, numerous mission patches, badges, and medallions, mugs, t-shirts, socks, a multi-purpose toolset, sunglasses, notebooks, and more! Source: author. My Key Impressions and Takeaways Florida (or at least Orlando) is really beautiful, and I can see why people willingly move here (it’s not just for Disneyland!). It also really lives up to its ‘Sunshine State’ name. Also a key factor is its all-around booming economy, space and otherwise. The space sector is a rapidly growing economy that affects every one of us, and has a lot of opportunities for everyone, regardless of background. To me, it’s clear that now really is the time to jump on the space bandwagon, it’s literally the future — who doesn’t want to be involved in that? We are becoming closer and closer to a space-faring species. Things that you see in sci-fi books and media, like holographic technology, quantum computing, permanent lunar/Martian habitation, asteroid mining, building things in space, space cities, space tourism, and more are very quickly becoming a reality. There is still a lot of work to be done, but we’re definitely getting there. There’s a lot of government and commercial support for these initiatives. There are a lot of opportunities for collaboration across government, industry, and academia, both domestically and globally. There seems to be a clear willingness by all parties to work together, but there needs to be better messaging and communication. Some of the technical challenges that exist in the field include big data (so much data is being generated from satellites, sensors, and other instruments, and it’s difficult to process and generate insights in real time), space domain awareness (it’s difficult to gauge depth when visually tracking small satellites, debris, and more, but computer vision can be used to help with depth perception, among many other uses), accurately predicting space weather (solar activity and emissions affect all of us on earth — especially if solar flares knock out GPS comms! It’s important to predict solar activity and other radiation events), and more. There are also a lot of ‘traditional’ data challenges, like lack of standards, lack of data governance and management, silos of data that don’t communicate with each other, unnecessary or incomplete data collection, data storage issues, and more. I think this is where roles like Chief Data Officer come in, because it’s very important to have a solid infrastructure and strategy for dealing with data to enable insight discovery, which enables better decision-making. For me personally, after talking to very smart people (field experts), I gained clarity on how I might combine my astronomy and data science skills to help solve these technological challenges in this sector. I also learned about industry and government organizations and companies that work in the space sector, the types of roles that exist, and skillsets that are currently in demand. With this knowledge, I can continue to build my knowledge about the space domain, and work towards a career in this space (no pun intended). I liked how this conference was run. The day starts with 2–3 keynotes, after which there are multiple breakout sessions. What I found unique about this was that most of the breakout sessions were panel discussions, with thought leaders and space experts engaging in a live discussion (and sometimes heated debates) in response to questions from the moderator and audience. It was very engaging and cutting-edge to hear first-hand informed opinions on how to tackle different challenges in this sector. The conference organizers did a splendid job with logistics too! Orlando + Florida This was my first time visiting Florida, and when I learned that Universal Studios and Disney World are located in Orlando where the conference is, I was so excited that I booked my stay for a few extra days beyond the conference! I stayed at the Castle Hotel, Autograph Collection, which was not too far from either Universal Studios, or the Orange County Convention Center where SpaceCom was held. It’s a very well-themed hotel, giving medieval vibes.</p> <p>The Castle Hotel I stayed at. Source: author. I bought a ‘2-park, 2-day + 2 days free’ pass to visit Universal Studios during my days off, mainly to visit the Harry Potter rides and shows. I also got to ride the Hogwarts Express between both parks!</p> <p>It’s Hogwarts castle! Source: author. My favorite rides: Harry Potter and the Forbidden Journey (I loved it so much that I rode it 5 times), Harry Potter and the Escape from Gringotts, and Revenge of the Mummy. These were all thrill rides, and I really enjoyed how they completely immersed me in the story.</p> <p>Hogsmeade village! I truly felt like a little Hogwarts student spending her day off browsing the shops of Hogsmeade. Source: author. In terms of shows, the Jason Bourne Stuntacular was absolutely amazing — it uses film, visual effects, actual actors, and more, and totally immersed me in the story. Encore please!</p> <p>DIAGONALLY! Oops, I meant Diagon Alley…! Source: author. I would be amiss if I did not mention the numerous Butterbeers I drank while walking around Diagon Alley, Hogsmeade, and Hogwarts. If Hagrid came up to me and said, “Yer a wizard, Aayushi!”, I would have totally believed him, because that’s how realistic-looking the sets were, and made me feel like I’m really part of the magical world (still waiting for my Hogwarts letter!).</p> <p>One of many Butterbeers I drank! Source: author. Universal Studios isn’t the only fun thing I did in Florida, I also visited the Kennedy Space Center! Located about an hour east of Orlando in Cape Canaveral, KSC is where NASA and SpaceX launch their rockets, assemble rockets in the Vehicle Assembly Building, and perform other operational duties. Located here is also Launchpad 39A, where the Apollo missions were launched.</p> <p>The Rocket Garden at Kennedy Space Center, with real rockets that were used for a variety of missions! Source: author. In the KSC Visitor Complex, I learned about the history of launches from here, including the Apollo missions and Space Shuttle Program, and upcoming NASA missions. I even got to be an astronaut and experience what it feels to launch to space in the Space Shuttle simulator! There were also a lot of really cool virtual reality (VR) experiences, including a game where NASA has a lunar base and my job is to mine moon rocks for regolith by blasting them.</p> <p>In the ‘Astronaut Encounter’ experience at KSC, I got to hear from Dr. Jan Davis, a former NASA astronaut, and her experience on the International Space Station! Source: author. Overall I really enjoyed my visit to KSC and learning about NASA’s great history of launches, and continued legacy of new launches with commercial partners like SpaceX and Blue Origin (as an aside: apparently Elon Musk frequently visits KSC for SpaceX launches, and was seen driving around in a Tesla Cybertruck, according to KSC employees)!</p> <p>A life-sized replica of the launcher for the Space Shuttle, outside the ‘Space Shuttle: Atlantis’ exhibit. Source: author. Closing Thoughts This was a very well-spent and enjoyable week in Florida for me! From the SpaceCom conference, I accomplished my goal of learning about the space industry landscape, and I now have a better understanding of how the space sector works.</p> <p>I also accomplished my goal of understanding how to potentially combine my astronomy and data science expertise by networking and talking with space thought leaders and experts, who pointed out numerous applications that require both skillsets. With my newfound understanding of the space sector, my next steps are to stay involved with the space community, and keep learning more.</p> <p>I also had a great time touring Florida, having spent 3 days at Universal theme park, and a day at Kennedy Space Center. I definitely need to come back again to visit the rest of Florida’s vast number of attractions and soak up that sunshine!</p> <p>This blog post by no means covers everything that I learned during my 3 short days at SpaceCom, but it has given me a lot of food for thought, which I look forward to thinking and reflecting about in the next few days, and pursuing new avenues of research. Here’s to space exploration!</p> <p>As a data scientist, I use <a href="https://www.tableau.com/">Tableau</a> a lot to make interactive dashboards for my business stakeholders to consume key insights. I realized that while I use Tableau a lot, there’s still a lot for me to learn — and what’s a better way to learn than attending a conference about it? In this article, I describe my experience attending the 2023 <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/tableau-conference/">Tableau Conference</a> in Las Vegas!</p> <p><em>Note: this article was originally drafted in May 2023, but finally published now in Feb. 2024!</em></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author posing in between larger-than-life DATA letters at conference, holding up a sign that says ‘I (heart) DATA’. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="what-is-tableauconference">What is Tableau/Conference?</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Example of a Tableau dashboard from one of its ‘stock’ demo examples. Source: Tableau. </div> <p>Tableau is a business intelligence software for making interactive dashboards. It’s a great way to provide stakeholders with an interactive (and often pretty-looking) interface to data, whether live or static. Tableau, as an organization, has a great community, and hosts this conference every year, even after <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/products/tableau/">SalesForce acquired the company</a>. The community very proudly refers to themselves as ‘<a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/products/tableau/">DataFam</a>’, and it was easy to see why, because the speakers and attendees at the conference were so vibrant and enthusiastic in their passion for data visualization.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Decor near conference’s main entrance. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="tableau-conference-2023">Tableau Conference 2023</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Registration area for conference. Source: author. </div> <p>The conference was hosted in Las Vegas from May 9–11 this year. I was surprised to learn that there would be more than 8000 people attending this year. There were so many events to choose from, including talks, workshops, community meet-ups, vendor booths, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8c6ZgrPR9Gk">Tableau Doctor</a>, <a href="https://www.tableau.com/blog/2023-iron-viz-2023-championship">IronViz Showdown</a>, Data Village, and more.</p> <p>As a result, I really had to focus on what exactly I wanted to accomplish by attending the conference. For me, this was learning about the more advanced features of Tableau, and how to approach problems and solutions in Tableau. This helped me choose the most relevant sessions, and I will summarize my key learnings from each of these below.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author’s scheduled sessions for conference. Author added multiple sessions in parallel to allow for flexibility, but wishes she had a time-turner to attend all of them simultaneously. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="my-experience">My Experience</h2> <p>At the time of attending the conference, I was working on building a Tableau dashboard at work, which needed to perform complex actions, called ‘<a href="https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/actions_sets.htm">set</a>’ and ‘<a href="https://help.tableau.com/current/pro/desktop/en-us/actions_parameters.htm">parameter</a>’ actions. These are functions for interacting with and passing data parameters to create interactivity in the dashboard. As a result, many of the sessions and workshops I attended were focused on learning about and using these set/parameter actions.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author attending a hands-on session (titled: A Producer’s Guide to Set Actions). Source: author. </div> <p>I also attended sessions about the art of data visualization and best practices, about using calculated fields, and even a Women in Data Strategy panel.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Women in Data Strategy panel. Source: author. </div> <p>The session that amazed me the most was the IronViz Competition, where three competitors had 20 minutes on-stage to create a dashboard from scratch! The energy in the stadium was incredible, and as we cheered on the three contestants, seeing their dashboard progress appear on the big screen, it was very nail-biting and lots of twists and turns right until the end!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Celebration of IronViz 2023 winner, Paul Ross. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="key-impressions-and-takeaways">Key Impressions and Takeaways</h2> <p>In the three short days I attended this conference, I learned a lot and interacted with a lot of amazing people. Some of my positive impressions:</p> <ul> <li>Huge DataFam community!</li> <li>Lots of inventive ways to use Tableau.</li> <li>Future integrations with LLMs, AI, etc.</li> <li>Very commercial — lots of vendor stalls.</li> <li>Need to think differently when using Tableau.</li> <li>There is so much that you can get out of Tableau Conference — it really depends on your reason for attending.</li> </ul> <p>Organizing large conferences is not an easy task, and I truly respect the organizers and volunteers who put in a lot of effort in making the conference a success. However, some of the things I wish they had done better:</p> <ul> <li>There were too many people, and not enough space in the session rooms.</li> <li>There were too many great sessions scheduled at the same time, so I had to miss out on a lot of these.</li> <li>Barely any sessions were recorded for later viewing.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photo from conference photobooth, with author holding up a sign that says ‘I (heart) DATA’. Source: author. </div> <p>In terms of my goal for attending the conference, which was to learn about using set and parameter actions, I definitely achieved it. I learned about different tools and methods to exploit set, parameter and dashboard actions to increase the interactivity and effectiveness of the dashboard. One of the ideas that was constantly reinforced was the idea of keeping the stakeholder in mind, and designing the dashboard to convey insights from the date as effectively as possible. Also, never be afraid to get creative!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Swag from Tableau Conference 2023. Includes t-shirts, notebook, fanny pack, stickers, badges, a really cute llama, and more. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="las-vegas--nevada">Las Vegas + Nevada</h2> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View from escalators when exiting Harry Reid International Airport after arrival in Las Vagas. Source: author. </div> <p>This was my first time visiting Las Vegas, so I was very excited! I stayed at the <a href="https://mgmgrand.mgmresorts.com/en.html">MGM Grand hotel</a>, and had the opportunity to explore the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Las_Vegas_Strip">Las Vegas Strip</a> on my days off. There were a lot of tourist-y attractions like <a href="https://www.mms.com/en-us/explore/mms-stores/las-vegas">M&amp;Ms Chocolate Factory</a>, <a href="https://hersheyschocolateworldlasvegas.com/">Hershey’s Chocolate Factory</a>, etc., but there were also a lot of other recognizable landmarks to see, like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fountains_of_Bellagio">Bellagio Fountain</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_the_Lion_(MGM)">Leo the Lion</a>, the mini <a href="https://newyorknewyork.mgmresorts.com/en.html">New York along the strip</a>, and more.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_the_Lion_(MGM)">Leo the Lion</a> outside of MGM Grand Hotel. Source: author. </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fountains_of_Bellagio">Bellagio Fountain</a> light and water show. Source: author. </div> <p>I also had the chance to visit the Hoover Dam, where I walked across the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_O%27Callaghan%E2%80%93Pat_Tillman_Memorial_Bridge">Mike O’Callaghan Pat Tillman Memorial Bridge</a> and got a spectacular birds-eye view of the Hoover Dam below me. I also visited the actual Hoover Dam, and learned about its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hoover_Dam">history, construction and legacy</a>, and got to see the power plant below the Dam.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Hoover Dam photos! Source: author. </div> <p>Overall, I really enjoyed my time in Vegas (and by extension, Nevada). The landscape was beautiful, and it was great experiencing that part of the country, since it’s very different from the East Coast. Next time I’m in the area, I will visit the Grand Canyon so I can also check off Arizona on my <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/aayushi.verma/viz/my_world_exploration_map/PlacesIveBeen?publish=yes">travel list</a>!</p> <h2 id="concluding-thoughts">Concluding Thoughts</h2> <p>Attending the Tableau Conference was very worthwhile, as I got to learn more about Tableau and how to do cool things with it. I have a better understanding now about advanced dashboarding actions, and bringing the best insights through well-designed dashboards. Some further reading:</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://godatadrive.com/blog/tableau-conference-2024">Tableau Conference 2024 - Everything You Need to Know Before You Go</a></li> <li><a href="https://sarahlovesdata.co.uk/2023/03/31/tableau-conference-guide-2023-data23/">Tableau Conference Guide 2023 #data23</a></li> <li><a href="https://sarahlovesdata.co.uk/2022/04/27/tableau-conference-attendee-guide-2022-data22/">Tableau Conference Attendee Guide 2022 #data22</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="conferences,"/><category term="space"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, I attended the SpaceCom Expo and Conference in Orlando, Florida. In this article, I talk about the conference, my experiences, and some other fun things I did in Florida!]]></summary></entry></feed>