<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-04T16:02:35+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aayushi Verma</title><subtitle>thinking slowly, learning deeply. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I Learned From My First Poster Competition</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned From My First Poster Competition"/><published>2025-03-12T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/first-poster-comp/"><![CDATA[<p>I recently participated in my <a href="https://dailycampus.com/2025/03/11/college-of-engineering-hosts-poster-competition/">university’s College of Engineering Annual Poster Competition</a>, and won 1st place for my department (Department of Computer Science and Engineering)! This poster competition is for graduate students (Master’s and PhD) to showcase our research in a visually-compelling manner, and present it in 3 minutes or less to faculty judges outside our departments. I had a fantastic time presenting my poster, and learning from other participants. Here’s what I learned from this amazing experience!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6507.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photo of author in front of her poster at the competition. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="1-plan-in-advance">1. Plan in advance.</h2> <p>As soon as I heard about the poster competition, I started planning my course of action, namely what project I’d be presenting about, and what part of the research I thought would be most interesting for the audience to hear about. Planning in advance also gave me the opportunity to keep thinking and brainstorming about my research and how to present a condensed yet effective story.</p> <h2 id="2-know-the-rules-and-guidelines">2. Know the rules and guidelines.</h2> <p>In order to start designing my poster, it was important to know the guidelines for the competition, including the poster size and layout, presentation time, and format of competition. Knowing this information helped me prepare my poster so that I follow the rules of the competition and avoid losing any points on technicalities.</p> <h2 id="3-prepare-and-practice-the-pitch">3. Prepare and practice the pitch.</h2> <p>Designing the poster itself was fairly easy (keep reading below for my specific design tips), but ultimately the poster is just a prop for me to convey my research to the competition judges. Therefore writing the pitch script is equally important and goes hand-in-hand with poster design (again, keep reading to learn how I wrote my pitch script). Once I wrote my pitch script and was satisfied with it, I practiced, practiced, practiced! I practiced in the shower, in the car, while walking to class, while doing the dishes – basically any moment of spare time I had, I practiced my pitch! The goal was not to memorize word-for-word the script, but rather to learn the flow of specific points in my story and key terms I wanted to say.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/CSE_Aayushi_Verma_v3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Low-res image of author’s poster. For a high-res version, click here. Source: author. </div> <h2 id="4-get-feedback-early-and-often">4. Get feedback early and often.</h2> <p>As soon as I learned about the competition, I spoke with my advisor and asked him for feedback on the research I wanted to present – we had a fruitful discussion on the key points of the research that are important, and this feedback was really helpful for me as I designed my poster and pitch. As I worked on developing my narrative, I often got feedback from my labmates, my research collaborators, my friends and family, and even my professor from the Scientific Communication class I took last semester! This variety of feedback and perspectives helped me hone my poster and pitch.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378380691_60fa0ec35c_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Author pitching her poster to the judges during the competition. Source: <a href="https://engineering.uconn.edu/">UConn College of Engineering</a>. </div> <h2 id="5-kiss">5. KISS.</h2> <p>Given that the poster presentation time was very short (3 minutes), I had to really think deep and convey only the most important things about my research. This meant Keeping Things Stupid Simple (KISS). I used the And, But, Therefore (ABT) storytelling framework to help me KISS. Essentially, the ABT framework is great for structuring your pitch so that it hooks the audience in, introduces the problem, and keeps them engaged to hear how you solved/are solving the problem. Read more about ABT in the ‘Resources’ section below.</p> <p>Another way I KISS-ed was by using the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs">Better Poster</a> format. This is a poster design format I like because of its visual simplicity, and focus on conveying key information in a visual manner. Essentially, the key takeaway in plain English should be placed in the middle of the poster, with 1-2 supporting key visuals. I’ve included the specific tips I used to design my poster in the ‘Resources’ section.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/IMG_6492.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Whiteboard brainstorm of author’s ABT storytelling for pitch. Source: author. </div> <p>These tips helped me prepare for the competition, but here are some things I also learned from the actual day of the competition:</p> <h2 id="6-wear-comfortable-shoes">6. Wear comfortable shoes!</h2> <p>I wore a professional outfit, which called for my high-heeled boots – but to my great dismay, these boots were not as comfortable as I thought, and by the end of the event, my feet were killing me! This was a little distracting (and painful), and I wish I had worn my flat boots, because we were standing the whole time during the event (4-5 hours straight!). Oh well, I’ll remember for next time!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-03-15-poster-comp/54378560999_8c6a951960_c.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Group photo of department and final winners of poster competition. Author standing far left. Source: <a href="https://engineering.uconn.edu/">UConn College of Engineering</a>. </div> <h2 id="7-have-alternative-versions-of-your-pitch">7. Have alternative versions of your pitch.</h2> <p>One of my greatest learnings during this competition was the necessity to “sell your science”. The ultimate winners of the competition had one thing in common: they were able to explicitly pitch their research as a sellable product to the final round judges, who were investors from industry. The judges asked them questions like, “What is the scalable value of your product?” and received dollar amounts in response. This was an eye-opening revelation for me, as thus far I had only viewed my research as “sharing knowledge to the community”, but in reality, an alternative version of this is also a market product! In fact, many common products we use today were indeed born from academia. This is also a great skill to have in academia itself, where you apply for scholarships, fellowships and grants to support your research – by identifying a clear, real-world “return on investment” from your research, it can help in making your application stand out to funding agencies.</p> <p>Later after the competition had ended, I went up and talked to the final winner: a final-year PhD student from Material Science &amp; Engineering, who presented their research on a color-changing nano-material which is lightweight and scalable – and I learned that they are already working on running 2 startups related to their research! I was fascinated hearing them talk about their journey and research – clearly they had put in the effort to really think about the real-world value of their research! One thing they recommended for learning about “selling your science” is by attending <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Startup_accelerator">seed accelerators</a> and seed pitches. Lucky for me, UConn has a great innovation program and hosts a monthly ‘Shark Tank’ style ‘Get Seeded’ event, which I’ll definitely attend to learn more about this new (to me) frontier!</p> <h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2> <p>Ultimately, my goal for taking part in the poster competition is because I love talking about my research, and learning about my peers’ research too! What’s a more fun way to do this than a poster competition? Furthermore this is great practice for conferences and building science communication skills – I highly recommend anyone to take part in such events – no matter what level you’re at (undergrad, Master’s, PhD, or beyond!). I especially love listening to the questions I get asked about my research – it helps me understand how others perceive my work, and enables me to better understand and explain my research. Finally, it’s a great way to connect with community and build a professional network!</p> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <h4 id="how-i-designed-my-poster">How I Designed My Poster</h4> <p>I used PowerPoint to design my poster! I used &gt;90pt font size for the big takeaway statement at the top, 60pt for headers, and 36pt for main body text. I chose a color palette of shades of blue, with an accent of orange for some contrast. I matched my bar chart of results to the same color palette, and matched keywords related to each of the columns of data as well, to make it visually easy to match up. I used <a href="https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/">QRCode Monkey</a> to generate the QR code which points to the project website, and <a href="https://coolors.co/">coolors.co</a> to choose colors for my palette! One thing I forgot to include in my final version is my name and department, as I had been cycling through different versions of my poster before settling on this one, whoops!</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/">https://www.qrcode-monkey.com/</a></li> <li><a href="https://coolors.co/">https://coolors.co/</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="better-poster">Better Poster</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYk29tnxASs</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/6ua4k">https://osf.io/6ua4k</a></li> <li><a href="https://betterposters.blogspot.com/2019/04/critique-morrison-billboard-poster.html">https://betterposters.blogspot.com/2019/04/critique-morrison-billboard-poster.html</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="and-but-therefore">And, But, Therefore</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERB7ITvabA4&amp;t=5s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERB7ITvabA4&amp;t=5s</a></li> <li><a href="https://katrinawesencraft.com/2021/08/11/creating-a-narrative-with-and-but-therefore/">https://katrinawesencraft.com/2021/08/11/creating-a-narrative-with-and-but-therefore/</a></li> </ul> <h4 id="3mt-3-minute-thesis">3MT (3-Minute Thesis)</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.animateyour.science/post/how-to-write-a-winning-3mt-script">https://www.animateyour.science/post/how-to-write-a-winning-3mt-script</a></li> <li><a href="https://threeminutethesis.uq.edu.au/resources/3mt-competitor-guide">https://threeminutethesis.uq.edu.au/resources/3mt-competitor-guide</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="science-communication"/><category term="conferences"/><category term="data-visualization"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently participated in my university's College of Engineering Annual Poster Competition, and won 1st place for my department (Department of Computer Science and Engineering)!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Power of Positive Thinking</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Power of Positive Thinking"/><published>2025-02-28T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2025/positive-thinking/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I was pondering whether the (metaphorical) glass is half-empty, or full.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/stock_half_full_or_empty_glass.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Half-full, or half-empty? Image source: <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/close-up-shot-of-a-glass-of-water-9996342/">pexels</a>. </div> <p>A half-empty glass: it is a true statement about the glass cup, and communicates the lack of water in the glass.</p> <p>A half-full glass: it is also a true statement about the same glass cup, and communicates the presence of water in the glass.</p> <p>Now replace ‘water’ with ‘opportunity’ in the above two statements: how would you rather see your glass cup now?</p> <p>Replace ‘glass cup’ with ‘life’, and re-read the above now.</p> <p>So positive thinking affects your worldview and opens up the world for you, if you see the glass as half-full: represents opportunity, knowledge, and the joy of living! It’s all about perspective, and how we choose to see things.</p> <p>Just a little thought for the day! 🙂</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2025-02-28-postive-thinking/glass_half_empty_or_full.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Message on a Post-It note the author wrote for herself as a reminder. Source: author. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="random"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago, I was pondering whether the (metaphorical) glass is half-empty, or full.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://awesomecosmos.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>